SAIMA SHARLEEN ISLAM

 J +880-1827537100
 ■ saimasharleen10@gmail.com

 in saimasharleen

saimasharleen saimasharleen

Objectives

A diligent, amiable, and articulate individual who is passionate about building up a flourishing research career across AI, Machine Learning and it's applications, Data Science, Computer Vision. I have mainly worked with machine learning algorithms and it applications in the field of data science. I bring with me, my strong passion for technology and quick learning capability.

Education

American International University-Bangladesh

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science & Software Engineering (CGPA: 3.42 /4.00)

May 2016 – Feb 2020 Dhaka, Bangladesh

Dhaka, Banqladesh

Work Experience

Cystem Arts Apr 2020 — Sep 2021

Software Engineer
• Assisted in development of the front end of a client's website.

• Collaborated with team members using version control systems such as Git to do the modifications.

American International University-Bangladesh

Sep 2019 — Dec 2019

Teaching Assistant

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Assisted the students in project for Advanced Topics In Programming III course
- Performed regular data entry tasks on students' evaluation grades

Battery Low Interactive Ltd.

Aug 2019 — Nov 2019

Intern, Web Development and Content Writing

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Collaborated with team members using version control systems such as Git to complete the assign tasks.
- Created different contents for the company.

Research Interests

Machine Learning, Deep Learning & its applications, Computer Vision, Bioinformatics, Medical Informatics

Research Experience

A Trend Analysis of crimes in Bangladesh

• The aim of this work is to analyse the crimes committed in the last ten years, establish relationships between the different types of crimes, and identify patterns between them.(Submitted to ICCA'22)

An adaptive Medical Cyber-Physical System model for post diagnosis patient care

• This work presents an adaptive system based on cloud and edge computing architecture and machine learning approaches to perform post-diagnosis medical tasks on patients, thus reducing the need for nurses, especially in the post-diagnosis phase. (Submitted to DASA'22)

UG Thesis: Human Detection in Crowd using Video Surveillance System

• Combined four methods to detect humans in-crowd in AIUB premises.

Publications

Journal Article:

• Saima Sharleen Islam, Md. Samiul Haque, M. Saef Ullah Miah, Talha Bin Sarwar, and Ramdhan Nugraha. "Application of Machine Learning Algorithms to Predict the Thyroid Disease Risk: An Experimental Comparative Study." (Accepted for Publication - PeerJ Computer Science) (Impact Factor: 1.39)

Conference Paper:

• Saima Sharleen Islam, Md Mahmudul Hasan Bhuiyan, Zahiduddin Ahmed, and Md Al-Amin. "An Empirical Survey on Crowdsourcing-Based Data Management Techniques." In Proceedings of the International Conference on Computing Advancements, pp. 1-7. 2020.

Standardized Tests

International English Language Test (IELTS):

Aggregate: 7, Listening: 8, Reading: 7, Speaking: 7, Writing: 6

Technical Skills

Languages: Python, C, C++, Java, c#

Database: SQL (MySQL,Oracle,Postgres), MongoDB

Tools: Git, VS Code, Jupyter Notebook, Google Colab, Overleaf, TeXworks, PyCharm, Mendeley

Libraries: Scikit-Learn, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, OpenCV

Web Technologies: Laravel, PHP, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Nodejs

Featured Projects

Extra Food Distribution Management System | HTML, CSS, Java script, Bootstrap, PHP, My SQL

- Overview: A platform for the Restaurant owner, Volunteer, Admin, Event Manager and General User. The owner can post for leftover foods, and a volunteer will pick up the foods and later will donate food in a specific location.
- Github Link: https://github.com/saimasharleen/Extra-Food-Distribution-Management-System-Web-Technologies-

Nirjhor | c++, opengl

- Overview: Nirjhor is basically a scenery-based project using opengl.
- Github Link: https://github.com/saimasharleen/Nirjhor-Graphics-Project-

3D liver segmentation | Pytorch, Monai

- Overview: Used machine learning and computer vision to find tumors in livers.
- Github Link: https://github.com/saimasharleen/3D-liver-segmentation

Scraping JavaScript Websites Using Splash | Python3, Splash

- Overview: Scraped two websites using splash.
- Github Link: https://github.com/saimasharleen/Scraping-JavaScript-Websites-Using-Splash-

Fashion $\mid bootstrap, css, javascript, html$

- Overview: Fashion is basically a web design project.
- Github Link: https://github.com/saimasharleen/Fashion-Web-Design

Visit Here For Full Project List

Online Courses

- 1. Web Scraping in Python Certificate Link
- 2. Introduction to Data Science in Python Certificate Link
- 3. IBM Data Science Professional Certificate: (On Going)
- **3.** AI for Medicine Specialization: (On Going)

Awards & Achievements

• Ada Lovelace Datathon 2021

Team Position: 8th Team Name: Panda-15

Standing Link: https://www.kaggle.com/c/alc-datathon-2021/leaderboard

• National Girls' Programming Contest 2018

Team Name: AIUB Incognito

Standing Link: https://algo.codemarshal.org/contests/ngpc18/standings

• The Duke of Edinburgh's International Award

The Bronze Standard

• Hult Prize at AIUB

2nd Runner Up

• World Literature Centre Book Reading Program

Winner

Extracurricular Activities

Firefox at AIUB

June 2018 - Feb 2020

Club Lead

Mentor

American International University-Bangladesh

- Managed executive board of 8 members and ran weekly meetings to oversee progress in essential parts of the chapter.
- Led chapter of 50+ members to work towards goals that improve and promote opensource and improve community service.
- Hosted six events in my university and one international event on behalf of Mozilla Bangladesh.

Hult Prize at AIUB

Aug 2018 – Dec 2018

Media And Publication Coordinator

American International University-Bangladesh

- Managed the events full media coverage.
- wrote all the media contents regarding the whole competition.

Leaping Boundaries

Feb 2017 - Sep 2018

 $Dhaka,\ Bangladesh$

- Taught soft-skills development exercises to 121 female school students in a 6th, 7th and 8th grade classroom.
- Coached a team of 3 students from 8th grades on Free I am Campaign attended by doctor, scientist and singer based in Bangladesh
- Taught 81 students from 6th grades on drawing artworks that represent their stories which are later integrated on the affiliated product line Taar- Connecting Stories.

10 Minutes School Feb 2018 – Jul 2018

Campus Ambassador

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Worked on different content regarding different educational topics.
- Promote online education on campus.

References

Md. Saef Ullah Miah

Assistant Professor $\begin{array}{l} Department\ of\ Computer\ Science \\ American\ International\ University-Bangladesh \\ \boxtimes \ saef@aiub.edu \end{array}$

Md. Al-Amin

Lecturer

Department of Computer Science
American International University-Bangladesh

⋈ alamin@aiub.edu

Dr. Dip Nandi

 $\label{eq:continuous} Professor\ and\ Director\\ Faculty\ of\ Science\ and\ Technology\\ American\ International\ University-Bangladesh\\ \boxtimes\ dip.nandi@aiub.edu$